The trend toward rationality and enlightenment was endangered long before the advent of the World Wide Web.
早在万维网问世很久以前，趋向理性与启蒙的潮流就已受到威胁。
As Neil Postman noted in his 1985 book Amusing Ourselves to Death, the rise of television introduced not just a new medium but a new discourse: a gradual shift from a typographic culture to a photographic one, which in turn meant a shift from rationality to emotions, exposition to entertainment.
正如尼尔·波兹曼在1985年出版的《娱乐至死》一书中所指出的，电视的兴起带来的不只是一种新媒介，还有一种新的话语方式：从印刷文化逐渐转向影像文化，这进而意味着从理性转向情感、从阐释转向娱乐。
In an image-centered and pleasure-driven world, Postman noted, there is no place for rational thinking, because you simply cannot think with images.
波兹曼指出，在一个以图像为中心、受享乐驱动的世界里，理性思维毫无容身之地，因为人根本无法用图像来思考。
It is text that enables us to “uncover lies, confusions and overgeneralizations, and to detect abuses of logic and common sense.”
正是文字使我们能够“揭穿谎言，看清糊涂观念和以偏概全之论，并识破对逻辑和常识的滥用”。
It also enables us “to weigh ideas, to compare and contrast assertions, to connect one generalization to another.”
文字还使我们能够“权衡各种观点，比较和对照不同论断，把一种概括与另一种概括联系起来”。
The dominance of television was not confined to our living rooms.
电视的主导地位并不局限于我们的客厅。
It overturned all of those habits of mind, fundamentally changing our experience of the world, affecting the conduct of politics, religion, business, and culture.
电视颠覆了所有那些思维习惯，从根本上改变了我们对世界的体验，影响了政治、宗教、商业和文化的运作方式。
It reduced many aspects of modern life to entertainment, sensationalism, and commerce.
它把现代生活的许多方面都降格为娱乐、煽情和商业。
“Americans don’t talk to each other; they entertain each other,” Postman wrote.
“美国人彼此之间不交谈，而是互相娱乐。”波兹曼写道。
“They don’t exchange ideas; they exchange images.
“他们不交流思想，而是交换图像。
They do not argue with propositions; they argue with good looks, celebrities and commercials.”
他们不用命题来论辩，而是用好看的外表、名人和广告来论辩。”
At first, the web seemed to push against this trend.
起初，万维网似乎在抵制这一潮流。
When it emerged towards the end of the 1980s as a purely text-based medium, it was seen as a tool to pursue knowledge, not pleasure.
20世纪80年代末，万维网作为一种纯文本媒介出现，当时被视为追求知识而非享乐的工具。
Reason and thought were most valued in this garden—all derived from the project of the Enlightenment.
在这片园地里，理性和思想最受重视——这一切都源自启蒙运动的事业。
Universities around the world were among the first to connect to this new medium, which hosted discussion groups, informative personal or group blogs, electronic magazines, and academic mailing lists and forums.
世界各地的大学属于最早接入这一新媒介的一批，这一媒介为讨论组、内容翔实的个人或团体博客、电子杂志以及学术邮件列表和论坛提供了平台。
It was an intellectual project, not about commerce or control, created in a scientific research center in Switzerland.
它是一项智识事业，无关商业或控制，创建于瑞士的一个科学研究中心。
And for more than a decade, the web created an alternative space that threatened television’s grip on society.
而且在十多年里，万维网开辟出了另一片天地，威胁着电视对社会的掌控。
Social networks, though, have since colonized the web for television’s values.
然而，此后社交网络已经让万维网变成了电视价值观的殖民地。
From Facebook to Instagram, the medium refocuses our attention on videos and images, rewarding emotional appeals—‘like’ buttons—over rational ones.
从Facebook到Instagram，这种媒介把我们的注意力重新集中到视频和图像上，奖励的是情感诉求——“点赞”按钮——而非理性诉求。
Instead of a quest for knowledge, it engages us in an endless zest for instant approval from an audience, for which we are constantly but unconsciously performing.
它不是让我们追求知识，而是让我们无休止地热衷于博取观众的即时认可；我们一直在为这些观众表演，只是自己并未意识到。
(It’s telling that, while Google began life as a PhD thesis, Facebook started as a tool to judge classmates’ appearances.)
（很能说明问题的是，Google最初是一篇博士论文，而Facebook起初是用来评判同学长相的工具。）
It reduces our curiosity by showing us exactly what we already want and think, based on our profiles and preferences.
它根据我们的个人资料和偏好，向我们展示的恰恰是我们本来就想要的东西、本来就持有的想法，以此削弱我们的好奇心。
The Enlightenment’s motto of ‘Dare to know’ has become ‘Dare not to care to know.’
启蒙运动的座右铭“敢于求知”，已经变成了“敢于不想求知”。